Guide to the Hettie Jones Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series II: Writings, 1956-2009
  - Subseries II.3: Prose, 1955-2009
    - From Midnight to Dawn, 1980s-2007
      - Chapter Drafts, 2004-2005
        - "Mary Ann Shadd", 2005 (Box 26, Folder 6)
        - "Chatham", undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
        - "Elgin", undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
        - "Niagara", undated (Box 26, Folder 9)
        - "Detroit Frontier", undated (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Research Materials, 2001-2004 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Reviews, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Royalties, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Doubleday Catalog Listing, 2007 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence, 2005-2006 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - No Woman No Cry, 2000-2004
      - Audio, undated --AV Sound Files--Digital Material, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Drafts, 2000-2003 (6 Folders) (Box 27, Folder 6 to 11)
      - Drafts, 2000-2003 (7 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Interview Transcriptions, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Jacket Copy, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Photos, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Proposal, undated (4 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 4 to 7)
      - Research Materials, 2000-2003 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Reviews, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 8)
      - Revisions, Expansions, and Additions, undated (2 Folders) (Box 28, Folder 8 to 9)
      - Revisions, Expansions, and Additions, undated (3 Folders) (Box 29, Folder 9 to 11)
      - Rita Marley Audio Interviews, undated (7 Audio Cassettes) (Box 55)
    - Book Reviews, 1990-1996
      - The Children Bob Moses Led, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Color of Water, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 7)
      - Love in Black and White, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - My First White Friend, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 9)
      - Pushed Back to Strength, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Voices in the Mirror, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - "Mama’s White", 1994-2001 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Permissions, 1983-2003
      - General, 1994-2001 (Box 30, Folder 13)
      - ICM, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 14)
      - Beat Down to Your Soul, 2000-2001 (Box 30, Folder 15)
      - A Different Beat, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, 1995-2003 (Box 30, Folder 17)
      - "Miscellaneous Literary Correspondence", 1983-1999 (Box 30, Folder 18)
      - Letter to Editor--by Hettie, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Women of the Beat Generation, 1995-1997
      - Correspondence, 1995-1997 (Box 30, Folder 21)
      - Drafts, 1996-1997 (Box 30, Folder 22)
      - Press, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Editorial Work, 1973-2000
      - Invoice, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 24)
      - Studio Museum Catalog, 2000 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Readings, 1960s-2009
      - Listings, 1981-2005 (7 Folders) (Box 31, Folder 1 to 7)
      - Listings, 1995-2001 (6 Folders) (Box 32, Folder 1 to 6)
      - Listings, 2002-2009 (6 Folders) (Box 33, Folder 1 to 6)
      - Listings, 2008-2009 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Oversize Reading Posters, 1960s-2008 (1 of 2) (Box 56, Folder 2)
      - Oversize Reading Posters, 1976-2003 (2 of 2) (Box 14-O-4)
    - Speeches, 1990-1997 (5 Folders) (Box 34, Folder 2 to 6)
    - Speeches, 1996-2001 (8 Folders) (Box 35, Folder 1 to 8)
    - Grants and Fellowships, 1994-2009 (2 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Writings About Hettie, 1981-2008
      - Academic Theses, 1988-2009 (4 Folders) (Box 36, Folder 3 to 6)
      - Articles, 1981-2008 (Box 36, Folder 7)
      - Articles, 1981-2008 (3 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 1 to 3)
      - Audio, Television, and Radio, 1991-2003 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Movies, 1988-2006 (2 Folders) (Box 37, Folder 5 to 6)
  - Subseries II.4: Children’s Literature, 1971-2002
    This subseries contains Jones' work on novels, short stories, textbooks, and educational pamphlets for children and young adults. Included are numerous complete manuscripts, typescripts, galleys, and proofs of many of Jones' works for children and young adults. There are also permissions and copyrights, correspondence, and contracts pertaining to the literature here. This subseries has been arranged according to its original order.
    - Royalties, 1971-2003
      - Big Star Fallin’ Mama, 1974-2003 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      - Longhouse Winter and Coyote Tales, 1973-1980 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - How to Eat Your ABC’s, 1977-1985 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - I Hate to Talk About Your Mother, 1982-1986 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Living with Wolves, 1974-1982 (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Trees, 1971-1999 (Box 37, Folder 12)
      - Elaine Markson, 1981-1989 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Drafts, 1973 (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 2 to 3)
      - Galleys, 1973 (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 4 to 5)
      - Proofs, 1974 (2 Folders) (Box 38, Folder 6 to 7)
      - Revisions, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Prepress Draft, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Revised Pages, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Catalogs, 1975-2001 (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1996 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - Dust Sleeves and Covers, 1973-1994 (Box 39, Folder 3)
      - Permissions and Rights, 1973-1993 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      - Press, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Research Materials, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Reviews, 1974-1975 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Coyote Tales, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - How to Eat Your ABC’s, 1976-1977
      - Manuscript and Proofs, undated (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Reviews and Letters, 1976-1977 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Braille Edition, undated--in oversize Box (Box 61-62)
    - Children’s Textbook, undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - I Hate to Talk About Your Mother, 1979-1984
      - Manuscripts, 1979-1980 (2 Folders) (Box 39, Folder 12 to 13)
      - Manuscripts, 1979-1980 (2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Hate and Fan Mail, 1981-1983 (Box 40, Folder 3)
      - Publicity, 1980 (Box 40, Folder 4)
      - Reviews, 1980-1984 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Longhouse Winter, 1972-1973
      - "The Bird, the Fish, the Snake, and the Man"--w/ letter from Hettie to her mother, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
      - "Longhouse Winter", undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
      - Proofs,undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
      - Reviews and Press, 1972-1973 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Spooky Tales from Gullah Gullah Island, 1995-1996 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Trees Stand Shining, 1970-2002
      - Library Notes, 1971 (Box 40, Folder 12)
      - Permission/Rights, 1970-2002 (Box 40, Folder 13)
      - Press Release, Award, Notes, Correspondence,1971-1997 (Box 40, Folder 14)
      - Reviews, 1971-1976 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Missing Sweet Rose, 1980-1981 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - A Person in Need of Supervision, 1980-1983
      - Manuscript--with letters from Delacorte, 1983 (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 40, Folder 17)
      - Manuscript, 1983 (1 of 2 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - Research Material, 1982 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Ring the Old Jeff Bell, 1980s (2 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Sister Duck and Brother Drake Find the Sun and the Stars, 1989- 1991 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Zora’s Gift, 1991 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Short Stories, 1961-1983
      - "Anasi the Spider", undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
      - "Niky but Different," 1973 (Box 41, Folder 8)
      - "The Emergency Signal," 1973 (Box 41, Folder 9)
      - "Gracie and the Biggest Pumpkin," undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - "Kellie’s Ordinary Thursday," 1961 (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - "Mahalia Jackson," undated (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - "Rosa Parks," 1969 (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - "The Sign in Beaver Hollow," undated (Box 41, Folder 14)
      - "The Summer House Secret," 1983 (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - "Sybil Ludington," undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Educational, 1975
      - At Home In the City, 1989-1991
        - Drafts ,Outlines, Notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
        - Correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 41, Folder 17)
      - Hunger, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 18)
      - Grace Opportunity Project, 1969-1983 (Box 41, Folder 19)
      - "Mobilization For Youth": History of Anti-Poverty Programs, undated (Box 41, Folder 20)
      - 101 Safety Hints for Children, undated (Box 41, Folder 21)
      - Second Grade Project Manual, undated (2 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 1 to 2)
      - Creative Living, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Exercises, undated (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - Sally Ride Biography, undated (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Subseries II.5: Yugen and Totem Press Materials, 1958-1963
    Included in this series are materials relating to Jones' time as co-editor of the little magazine Yugen, and the poetry press Totem. Issues of Yugen between 1958 and 1959, as well as the financial record book which includes a partial distribution list are here. The subseries also has a number of poetry submissions sent to Yugen, and some Spanish-language poetry books inscribed to the magazine.
    - Yugen Issues, 1958-1959 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Financial Record Book, circ.1963 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Submissions to Yugen, 1958-1962
      - Anonymous, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Bob Nichols, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Jorge Frick, undated (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Stan Persky, 1958-1962 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - Micheline, Jack and George Stade, undated (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Spanish Language Journals and Chapbooks Inscribed to Yugen, circ. 1963 (Box 42, Folder 12)
- Series III: Personal and Family Materials, 1895-2009
  This series contains material relating to Jones' early life and family history. Among the documents are early Cohen family records such as immigration and confirmation documents from the late Nineteenth and early Twentieth Century; and elementary school, high school and university materials, including reports, school certificates, programs and scripts from high school and college plays, and Jones' undergraduate thesis. Finally, documents that pertain to Jones' fight to retain her residence at 27 Cooper Square, New York City, in the 1990s can be found here.
  - Cohen Family, 1895-2004
    - General, 1979-2004 (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Family Records, 1916-1964 (Box 42, Folder 14)
    - Family Records--Immigration, Confirmation Records, 1895-1947 (Box 14-O-4)
  - Hettie, 1941-2009
    - School Report "Linen", 1943 (Box 42, Folder 15)
    - Concert Programs, 1944-1946 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - School Certificates and Programs, 1947-1951 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Undergraduate Thesis, 1955 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - College Yearbook--University of Virginia, 1955 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - College Related, 1951-1992 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Café au Lait Script, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - College Writing, 1954-1955 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Tenant Statement 27 Cooper Sq., 1962 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Judson Poets’ Theatre%tb %te Pr gram, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - Medical, 1962-2004 (Restricted until 2054) (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Mexico Trip, 1995 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - 27 Cooper Square, 2007-2009 (Box 43, Folder 10)
- Series IV: Printed Materials, 1941-2000s
  This series holds printed materials collected by Jones, but produced, for the most part, by others. A large number of print announcements and advertisements for events across the arts—primarily visual arts, literature, film, and music—dating from the 1970s through the 2000s are here. This series also brings together a collection of little magazines from the 1960s through the 2000s, including a nearly five-year run of the Gloucester, Massachusetts poetry journal Bezoar from the late 1970s and 1980s. Aside from little magazines, there are also magazines and journals relating to music—primarily jazz—mostly from the 1950s, and a number of political and radical magazines from the 1960s and 1970s. Finally, this series contains numerous pieces of visual art, primarily paintings and drawings, including some done by Jones.
  - Arts Events Announcements, 1950s-2000s
    - Art Shows, 1950s-2000s (4 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Music/Dance/Theatre/Film, 1950s-2000s (4 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Literary, 1970s-2000s (2 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Chapbooks, Mimeo Magazines, and Broadsides, 1970s-2000s
      - General, 1970s-2000s (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Alternative Press, 1990-1998 (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - The Floating Bear #25, 1962 (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - SOS Int’l, 1991-1992 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Books by Hettie Jones, 1971-2009 (Box 61-62)
    - List, 2010 (Box 54)
  - Literary Magazines, 1941-1993
    - A Gathering of the Tribes, 1991-1993 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Bezoar, 1975-1977 (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 4 to 5)
    - Bezoar, 1977-1981 (4 Folders) (Box 44, Folder 1 to 4)
    - The Fuse, 1992 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Giants Play Well in the Drizzle, 1983-1992 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Ikon, 1968 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Noose, 1982 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - # Magazine, 1978-1981 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Ritual and Dissent, 1983 (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Sensitive Skin, 1992-1993 (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Tamarind, 1994 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Unmuzzled Ox--with note and chapbook by Michael Andre, 1988 (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - Music Magazines, 1941-1968
    - Abundant Sounds, 1964 (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - American Jazz Festival Newport Program, 1957 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - ASCAP Today, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Folk Review of Peoples Music, 1945-1964 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Jazz, 1962-1965 (2 Folders) (Box 45, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Jazz Information, 1941 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Jazz Journal, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Jazz Magazine, 1961 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Jazz Podium, 1962 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Jazz Review, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Les Lettres Francaises, 1968 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - The Record Changer, 1948-1957 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Record Research, 1956-1963 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Political/Radical Magazines and Publications, 1963-1976
    - Black Radical Journals, 1963-1965 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - The Razor, 1964 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Weather Underground Publications, 1971-1976 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Visual Art, 1949-2003
    - General, circ. 1970s-1980s (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Anonymous, undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Art by Hettie, 1949-1980
      - Costume and Character Illustrations, undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Drawings, 1957-1980 (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Scratchboard Drawing, circ.1949-1950 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Birthday, undated (Box 14-O-4)
    - Domenic Capobianco, 1965 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Fielding Dawson, 1958-1959 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Howard Kennerty, undated (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Sara Perkoff, undated (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Tomi Ungerer, undated (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Tatiana Weinstein--Correspondence and Portraits of Hettie, 1997-2003 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Tibor de Nagy, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
- Series V: Teaching Materials, 1982-2009
  Reflecting several decades as a teacher at colleges, universities, and prisons, this series holds documents relating to writing workshops, led by Jones, at various institutions from the early 1980s to the 2000s. Materials include syllabii and other teaching material, drafts of Jones' collections of prison writing, and correspondence with students.
  - Subseries V.1: Prison, 1982-2008
    The material relating to Jones' work as a writing teacher in a number of different prisons, as well as her work with the PEN Prison Writing Committee, is contained in this subseries. Included are syllabi, assignments and other handouts, correspondence with students, examples of student work, and grant proposals. Another major part of this subseries is the material—mostly drafts and correspondence—relating to three books edited by Jones of prison workshop writing, Words Over Walls, More in than Out and Aliens at the Border. Also here are a number of cassette recordings of poetry readings at prisons, recorded in the 1990s.
    - Correspondence, 1982-2009 (2 Folders) (Box 48, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Bedford Hills Correctional Facility Writing Workshop, 1989-2002
      - Teaching Materials, 1989-2002
        - Articles, 1995-1999 (Box 48, Folder 3)
        - Business Correspondence, 1989-2002 (Box 48, Folder 4)
        - Syllabi and Lessons, 1989-1990 (Box 48, Folder 5)
      - Grants, 1989-2000
        - Arts, 1989-1997 (Box 48, Folder 6)
        - Grant Proposals, 1992-2000 (Box 48, Folder 7)
        - Grant-Funded Events, 1998-1999 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Aliens at the Border, 1995-2007
      - Correspondence, 1995-2007
        - Release and Order Forms, 1995-2007 (Box 48, Folder 10)
        - Publishing, 1996-1997 (Box 48, Folder 11)
      - Copyright, 1997 (Box 48, Folder 12)
      - Flyers and Order Forms, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 13)
      - Reviews, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 1)
      - Unused Pieces, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 2)
      - Video Correspondence and Documents, 1997-2002 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - More in than Out, 1991-2000
      - Copyright, 1992 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      - Original Published Version, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 6)
      - Reviews, 1992-1994 (Box 49, Folder 7)
      - SPD, 1997-2000 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Bedford College Project, 1993-1999
      - Correspondence, 1993-1999 (Box 49, Folder 9)
      - Syllabus and Student Writing, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 10)
      - "Dance of the Mind Among Words," 1999 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - PEN Prison Writing Committee, 1991-2008
      - Charles Norman, 2005-2008 (Box 49, Folder 12)
      - Conference on "Death and Dying in Prisons and Jails," 1998 (Box 49, Folder 13)
      - General Correspondence, 1991-2004 (Box 49, Folder 14)
      - Grant Proposals, 1991 (Box 49, Folder 15)
      - PWC Annual Writing Awards for Prisoners, 1990-2002 (2 Folders) (Box 50, Folder 1 to 2)
      - PWC Radio Broadcasts, 1999-2001 (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Words Over Walls, 1998-2000
        - Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 50, Folder 4)
        - Drafts, 1998 (Box 50, Folder 5)
        - Proofs, 1998 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Writing Workshops, 1988-2004
      - General,, 1999-2001 (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - Eastern Correctional Institute, 1997-2000 (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - Louisiana Prison, 1999 (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - Noise! Women, Writing, and Incarceration, 2004 (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - Sing Sing, 1988-1989 (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - Taconic, 1994-1995 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Poetry Reading Recordings, 1991-2000 (8 Audio Cassettes) (Box 57)
  - Subseries V.2: University Courses and Community Workshops, 1984-2009
    Held in this subseries is material from Jones time as a teacher in universities, colleges, and community based writing programs. The material includes syllabi, assignments and classroom handouts, and examples of student work, as well as flyers and other advertisements for various universities of the various courses she taught. Following Jones' own organization, the documents are arranged alphabetically by school under the headings "Semester-Long Courses" and "Workshops", with the exception of Parsons and SUNY-Stonybrook.
    - Caring Community, 2009 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1990-2007 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Guest Lectures and Thesis Advisement, 1999-2005 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Parsons, 2003-2005 (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 5 to 6)
    - Riverstone, 2009 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Rosters and Grades, 1997-2007 (restricted until 2087) (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - SUNY Purchase, 2002-2005 (3 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 1 to 3)
    - Students Work, 2003-2006 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Semester-Long Classes, 1994-2007 (5 Folders) (Box 52, Folder 5 to 9)
    - Workshops, 1984-2009 (3 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 1 to 3)
- Series VI: Audio, Visual, and Photographic Materials, 1918-2000s
  This series comprises cassettes, VHS tapes, and photographs pertaining to Jones' personal life and literary career. The VHS tapes contain recordings of Jones' appearances on various documentaries and television shows, primarily relating to the Beat/Downtown New York literary scene. The cassette tapes primarily consist of recordings of Jones' radio appearances and interviews, as well as public readings of her works.
  The bulk of this series consists of photographs, which include images of the Cohen family from the early Twentieth Century, and also a large number of Jones during college. The largest set of photographs are those of Jones taken during the Fifties and Sixties in New York City's East Village, and includes photos of her then-husband LeRoi Jones, her children Kellie and Lisa, and a number of other New York City writers and artists. Many of the photographs were originally arranged in scrapbooks, and, when possible, this order has been maintained.
  - Audio, 1979-2000
    - Cassettes, 1979-2000
      - Interviews and Readings, 1979-1998 (18 Audio Cassettes) (Box 58)
      - Interviews and Readings, 1998-2000 (9 Audio Cassettes) (Box 57)
  - VHS, 1992-2001 (14 Tapes) (Box 60)
  - Photos, 1918-2000s (Box 63)
    - General, 1995, Undated (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - General, 1970s-1980s (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Childhood and University, 1930s-1950s (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Cohen Family, 1918-1970s (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Hettie, 1940s-2000s (5 Folders) (Box 59, Folder 4 to 8)
    - Jones Family, 1940s-1980s (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Photocopies, circa 1918-2000s (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Oversized, 1960s-1990s (Box 56, Folder 5)
- Series VII: LeRoi Jones/Amiri Baraka Material, 1940s-2004
  Contained in this series are materials directly pertaining to Jones' husband LeRoi Jones (later Amiri Baraka). Items range from personal items, such as Jones' military records, to a small number of typescript and manuscript drafts of unpublished and published poems by LeRoi Jones from the late 1950s and early 1960s. This series also includes correspondence between LeRoi Jones and Hettie and their children, Kellie and Lisa, as well as a number of flyers and even notices which belonged to LeRoi Jones. This series has been organized alphabetically.
  - General, 1956-1965 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - "An Organization of Young Men" Flyers, 1961 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Audio--"McClure Whalen Olson Jones in Gloucester", undated (Box 57)
  - Correspondence, 1960s-2004
    - General, undated (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Hettie, 1960s-2004 (4 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 7 to 10)
    - Kellie and Lisa, 1960s (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Jones Family, 1963-2009 (3 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 12 to 14)
    - Jones Family, 1963-2009 (1 Folder) (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Events and Flyers, 1960s-1984 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Hettie, 1959-1965 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Military Records, 1954-1958 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Printed Material, 1964-1986 [1 of 2] (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Printed Material, 1963-1985 [2 of 2] (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Photos--Jones Family, 1940s-1980s (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Resumes, 1956-1963 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Spanish Language Journal and Chapbooks--Inscribed to LeRoi, 1960s (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - "Tribute to Black Poets By Black Poets", 1965 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Writing, 1956-1964
    - Published, 1960-1964 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - Unpublished, 1956-1961 (Box 54, Folder 10)